Welcome back to a push in under 3
minutes. No time for intros. Let's get
into it. World War II was just simply
devastating. Around 80 million people
will die over the course of this 6-year
long war. However, the thing about this
war from a US history perspective is
that this war was pretty much fought
everywhere except the US. After the war,
Europe and Asia will be devastated in
both casualties and land. I mean, just
look at these images on the screen. So
now the US will have a massive military,
industrial capacity and mostly untouched
land meaning finally the United States
will emerge as the most powerful country
in the world upon the conclusion of this
war. The Yelta and Potam conferences
will happen near the end of the war. The
key outcomes you should know are that
Germany will be divided into occupation
zones. Japan will be occupied and
rebuilt under US supervision. War crime
trials will be held against Nazi leaders
and borders/governments across Europe
and Asia will be reorganized. The other
consequence of this war is the creation
of the United Nations or UN. This will
allow countries to negotiate, prevent
wars, and promote cooperation. But very
quickly, you'll see the Soviet Union
occupy most of Eastern Europe, enforce a
communist ideology, which will lead to a
different kind of war that we refer to
as being very cold. But I think we'll
cover that next unit. On the screen now,
AP style questions for this topic.
Pause. Now,
I'll put the answers on the screen now.
What a unit this has been. And I will
truly see you next unit for unit 8.